Camie Kim communication that works

WEB camiekim.github.io • E-MAIL contact.camie@gmail.com

I have 20 years of experience as a technical writer and application developer. I can offer a superb command of the English language, analytical and programming skills, an educated and well-honed sense of design aesthetics, and the energy and drive to learn more.

EXPERIENCE

Agfa HealthCare, Technical Writer

2005 – present, Waterloo, Ontario

Agfa provides diagnostic imaging and healthcare IT solutions. Working with a global team of product managers, developers, testers, and other writers, I write DITA-compliant XML and produce HTML help and PDFs for an audience of end-users, service engineers, and developers. I have written content for both front and backend systems, documenting web services, scripts, configuration and load balancing guides, installations, migrations, and upgrades of complex systems, and more.

Sun Life Insurance Co., Application Developer II, I

1999 – 2005, Waterloo, Ontario

Full-cycle mainframe application development in an IBM OS/390 environment: TSO/ISPF, PL/1, IMS, DB2, MQ Series, SAS, SQL, JCL, Zeke, and other mainframe utilities and middleware technologies.

Collaborated with architects, software engineers, business system analysts, and testing specialists to deliver high quality solutions for large-scale applications and systems.

Provided on-call support for the production environment on a rotating schedule.

The Mutual Group, Technical Writer, Admin Assistant

1996-1999, Waterloo, Ontario

Initially hired as a temporary admin assistant, after less than a year, I applied for an internal posting and began working as a technical writer.

Using Adobe RoboHelp, Word, and other desktop publishing tools, wrote, edited, and published various online help files, tutorials, introductory materials, and promotional documents for software used by the sales force.

The Fields Institute, Executive Assistant

1994/95, Toronto, Ontario

Assisted the two co-directors of this mathematical research institute, including scheduling, making all travel arrangements, organizing regular seminars, editing and distributing a monthly newsletter, and assisting in the preparation of grant proposals and academic papers.

EDUCATION M.A. In English

Concordia University, Montréal, Québec

B.A. In English, First Class

University of B. C., Vancouver, BC

- U.B.C. Scholarship
- B.C. Post-Secondary Scholarship
- Hawk Eilertson Scholarship

Continuing education

Conestoga College, Kitchener-Waterloo, Ontario

C++, Java, C Programming Language, Advanced Visual Basic, Visual Basic, Problem Solving & Programming Concepts, Internet Graphics

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Ontario

Intro to JavaScript, Intro to SQL & Relational Databases

S.F.U. Centre for Studies in Publishing, Vancouver, BC

Desktop Publishing via Adobe PageMaker

Hartnack Schule, Berlin, Germany

German language studies

Université à Trois Rivière, Trois Rivière, Québec

French language studies

....and numerous webinars and online courses (Society for Technical Communication, Pluralsight, Code School, among others)

SKILLS Expert in DITA, HTML, oXygen, XMetal.

Experienced in Bootstrap, CSS, DITA-OT, FrameMaker, Markdown, Plain language, XPath, XQuery, XSLT, YAML.

Knowledgeable in Agile software development, JavaScript, Jekyll, jQuery, JSON, OpenAPI, PHP, Postman, SQL, SVG, Swagger, XML (DTD, Schema).

MORE

I am an award-winning creative writer and my works of fiction have appeared in several literary journals and anthologies. I love to bake and I also enjoy reading, travelling, and hot yoga.

- Author of "Cartography", Scribner's Best of the Fiction Workshops, the inaugural volume in a series presenting the best short fiction culled from over one hundred prestigious writing programs around the United States and Canada. Simon & Schuster Inc., New York, 1997
- Recipient of a Canada Council for the Arts Literary Arts Development Program grant. Canada Council for the Arts, 1996
- Winner, Writers' Union of Canada Short Prose Competition for New Writers, for "Travelling", published in Books in Canada. Canadian Review of Books Ltd., Toronto, 1994

REFERENCES Available upon request.